<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mohammed Touban</title>
    <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mohammed Touban</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 11:45:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Reactive Programming</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/presentation/android-reactive-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 11:45:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/presentation/android-reactive-programming/</guid>
      <description>A quick look at some of the ways RxJava can make development easier and more enjoyable (specifically for Android). This talk was presented at Google devfest Lebanon 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dagger2 in the Real World</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/post/real-dagger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 18:02:23 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/post/real-dagger/</guid>
      <description>Dagger and Dagger2 may be things you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of if you&amp;rsquo;re an Android developer. Dependency injection has been a hot topic for a while now. Often the examples you see are solving complex architectural problems, or are too trivial to demonstrate applicability.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a real world example of how Dagger2 is used in Emergency AUS, and maybe spark some ideas for where Dagger could improve your existing code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4Genies</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/4genies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/4genies/</guid>
      <description>Built at Aiia-Solutions. 4Genies is neutral and independent self-care app for mobile subscriber in the GCC countries. 4Genies revolutionized the recharge process for prepaid customers by allowing them to seamlessly recharge a voucher by taking a picture and automatically recognize the numbers and perform the recharge command for each operator.
4Genies allows user to better control their telecom budget by providing detailed charts of their telecom usage on both calls and data usage with a daily, weekly and monthly view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaan News App</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/alaan-news-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/alaan-news-app/</guid>
      <description>Built for an online contest for best news application competition for an AlAan TV which is a Dubai-based free-to-air pan-Arab channel focusing on issues that matter to Arab women. In this application, you can view AlAan TV shows schedule, find some details about the shows and videos of the news (Akhbar Al Aan) and shows. You can also watch Al Aan TV live from your device. Some of other features include:   Connectivity and user engagement  Live news accessibility  Round the clock news accessibility  Access news Online/ Offline  Analytics &amp;amp; Feedback System  Ability to customize (which news to receive)  Follow up the latest news minute by minute and receive breaking news directly pushed to your home screen  Follow up news happening as well as world news, sport, health, money &amp;amp; business, science &amp;amp; technology and entertainment news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Butlr</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/butlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/butlr/</guid>
      <description>Under development at Ideatolife. Butlr is a luxury concierge service devoted to saving time in someone’s busy life! The platform provides an on-demand delivery, which can include sweet treats, documents, laundry, repairs, shopping, gifts or even any pick up!
The app is currently in development phase and completely written in kotlin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carry</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/carry/</guid>
      <description>Built at Ideatolife for an on-demand delivery startup based out of Dubai, UAE. Carry is driven via an app that customers can download to their smartphones for both Android and iOS.
You simply pin the location and destination of your package, provide some info on its size and how fragile it is, schedule when you would like the delivery to occur and a driver will be dispatched within the hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carry Assistant</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/carry-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/carry-assistant/</guid>
      <description>Built at Ideatolife for an on-demand delivery startup based out of Dubai, UAE. Carry is driven via an app that drivers can download to their smartphones for both Android and iOS.
Anyone with access to a vehicle can become a Carry Assistant! Whether you are a freelancer, a student, or simply want to make the most of your extra time, just apply with us and we’ll get you started on our platform to help deliver the best experience to our customers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feed</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/feed/</guid>
      <description>Under development at Ideatolife.
The app is currently being rewritten from scratch using kotlin with design uplifting and new functionalities!
Engage in social media activity with your friends &amp;amp; family via Feed App and get rewards such as Buy One Get One Free offers, 2 for 1 voucher, food deals &amp;amp; discounts and free stuff at your favourite places in Dubai, U.A.E.
Stay updated with Feed to keep yourself notified about the latest promotions &amp;amp; events in town from a wide array of cafes, lounges &amp;amp; restaurants around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gruptour</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/gruptour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/gruptour/</guid>
      <description>Built at Ideatolife for a startup based out of Beirut, Lebanon. Gruptour is a platform that help small group organizers to manage the trip, to share the itinerary with their customers, solicit customer feedback, and much more.. I have built both the backend (using PHP laravel) and the mobile app.
Founded in December 2015, GrupTrip S.A.L. is a young tech company on a mission to provide the best smartphone experience for travelers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heer</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/heer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/heer/</guid>
      <description>Built at Ideatolife. Heer is a moment-based rewards SDK which adds value and innovation to the offline shopping experience. It uses an online platform which will engage with the target audience through personalized rewards. The system relies on the estimote beacons installed in the mall shops. The platform provide the following features:  Personalized online/offline experience for customers Store analytics  Moment based customer engagement Shopper Behavior</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library App</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/library-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/library-app/</guid>
      <description>Built at Scryptech.The application provides the possibility of downloading, fully display, browse and search the library&amp;rsquo;s books. These days the app is looking a little dated with its Holo era design, but it still functions just fine. Check it out in Google Play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medstew</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/medstew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/medstew/</guid>
      <description>Built at Scryptech. MEDSTEW® is designed for students and tutors in the healthcare field. Users will be able to connect with fellow medical students, tutors, and entire institutions from all over the world. The application uses colourful forms and tabs to make documenting a full history, examination, and investigations easy. It also automatically presents the data in a clear, comprehensive, single page format. The application enables users to search cases across the entire MEDSTEW® community and enables them to store relevant clinical cases to help them meet their study objectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onlivery</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/onlivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/onlivery/</guid>
      <description>Built at Ideatolife. It&amp;rsquo;s an online food delivery app. Order and customize meals from over 750 restaurants. Fancy a pizza, a burger, or even Chinese? Onlivery is your ultimate solution to order food online. Download Onlivery now for free and get instant access to the best, most diverse interactive restaurant directory in Lebanon. It&amp;rsquo;s free to use with no added cost and saves you the hassle of long delivery phone calls with restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Taxi ME</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/smart-taxi-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/smart-taxi-app/</guid>
      <description>Built at Aiia-solutions.Smart Taxi or Lyft of Arab world ! is an ingenious application architected and conceived in the region, in order to best serve the specific needs &amp;amp; requirements of taxi users in the GCC Countries in particular as well as the Arab world in general.
Features  Select pickup location Taxi Info Live tracking of taxi driver Call your taxi driver notification for driver status 
These days the app is looking a little dated with its Holo era design, but it still functions just fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThatuApp</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/thatu-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/thatu-app/</guid>
      <description>Built as a freelance project, ThatuApp is a free and an anonymous chatting application without disclosing your identity. Only identify yourself with a color of your choice and start chatting with strangers nearby or anywhere in the world. You can freely share secrets, personal views, silly jokes or even gossip with no regrets or records.
Features:  ANONYMOUS CHATTING COLOR IDENTIFICATION NEAR OR FAR NO REGRETS, NO RECORDS FAVORITES</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TopShou</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/topshou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/topshou/</guid>
      <description>Built at Ideatolife, Topshou is a community-driven fashion discovery platform. Users get the opportunity to inspire, get inspired, and seek the community’s advice on what to wear. They can also discover what to purchase in order to complete their trendy looks. The platform includes professional fashion experts and actual brands to offer an exclusive experience.
The app can be found in Google Play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHO - Measures</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/who-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/who-measures/</guid>
      <description>Built at Ideatolife, the purpose of this application is to report any possible event against health care system in Iraq. The app has completely written in kotlin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zain Cash Agent</title>
      <link>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/zain-cash-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhdtouban.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/zain-cash-agent/</guid>
      <description>Built at Ideatolife, this app was built for a leading telecom client based out of Iraq. Zain has thousands of agents that use the app to do various e-payment transactions.
Zain Cash is a mobile wallet, money transfer, electronic bill payment, funds disbursement service, licensed by the Central Bank of Iraq and launched in late 2015 by Zain and Iraq Wallet. ZainCash allows users to deposit, withdraw, transfer money and pay for goods and services via their mobile phone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>